Ricardo Jorge Fernandes da Silva Carlos (32)

Porto, Portugal (can relocate) +351 913 387 296 • Skype: ricardo.j.carlos@gmail.com • email • LinkedIn <u>GitHub - Portfolio</u>

Personal statement

I am transitioning from the Airline Industry, where I worked for the past 6 years, to Web & Mobile Developer and at present, I am looking to join a small team where I can learn, use my skills acquired and start as a junior developer. I'm challenging myself to always be up to date on the technological landscape with my self-learning ability.

In November 2016, I decided that I want to go for something more challenging than the work I was doing. I was always fascinated with programming and Mobile environments but never got around doing that. So, since then, I have been learning how to code and have gotten familiar with various parts of the Front end and Back end side of the development. I recently finished a course of Web & Mobile developer, which includes HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript and the Framework Bootstrap; Multi-Platform Mobile Application Development using Cordova, Ionic, Node.js, AngularJS; CMS of which Drupal and WordPress; Native Java Development for Android, SEO / SEM and more recently I'm finishing to learn AngularJS with the Ionic Framework for mobile development.

I'm a conscientious and professional person, with extremely high standards and eye for details, currently seeking a position that will make use of acquired skills with and opportunity for growth. A highly methodical and efficient individual, whose thorough and precise approach to work has yielded excellent results.

Key Skills

- · Proactive person who is able to work effectively under my own influence and stressful conditions
- Excellent communication skills, both written and verbal
- Self-motivated, efficient with high attention to details
- Problem-solving attitude
- Flexible in assignments
- Good eye for design
- Honest, dependable, reliable
- Fluent on Spanish and English, native Portuguese.

Employment History

Web Developer – Orbitur/Laminar Madeiras, Porto – Portugal (Internship)

(October 2017 – December 2017)

Responsibilities:

- Redesign Laminarmad.com website using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Bootstrap, AngularJS and PHP;
- Good UX and modern design;
- Improving performance and accessibility;
- Lower the maintenance effort later on;

Flight and Traffic Coordinator, Load Controller/Load Planner, Sky Handling Partner, London - UK (November 2014 – November 2016)

Achievements and responsibilities:

- Responsible for overseeing and co-ordinating the safe unloading/loading of the aircraft;
- Supervision, assistance with passenger services and passengers being directed to and from the aircraft in a safe manner;
- Weight and balance of aircraft, to include the loading instruction to ramp staff;
- Co-ordinating & recording the safe and timely delivery of all services to the aircraft including: Catering, Fuelling, Engineering, Cleaners, Toilet/Water servicing, Crew Transport and ground equipment;
- Responsible for the safe co-ordination of the pushback/start-up procedure on departure of the aircraft;
- Responsible for the timely sending of all movement messages following the aircrafts departure.
- LUFTHANSA OPS Basic Aircraft Handling Ramp Narrow Body and LH Regional Aircraft Certificate, issued by Lufthansa at Seeheim on December 2015.

Traffic Agent (Supervisor) / Air Transat SCM, Swissport, Porto - Portugal

(January 2014 – October 2014)

Achievements and responsibilities:

- Provide logistical coordination and services for FBO Corporate Aircraft, Charter, Military and Head of State Aircrafts;
- Ensuring that productivity and performance criteria are met in the designated areas of responsibility including fulfilling regular performance and quality assessment reports;
- Making recommendations on all aspects of company ground handling operations whilst seeking to identify
 opportunities and improve performance and productivity;
- Diary management, typing documents, making weekly/monthly reports.

Traffic Agent / Air Transat SCM, Servisair, Porto - Portugal

(*November 2010 – December 2013*)

Achievements and responsibilities:

- Supervise the check-in/ticketing/gate operations of all assigned flights
- Managing incoming requests for Executive Flights/Private Aircraft Operations
- Oversaw the daily ramp operations and provided leadership and support to all front-line staffing
- Worked with corporate management to maximize operational performance in areas of on-time performance
- Maintained a high level of customer service

Education

CESAE, Porto – Web & Mobile Developer (500h)

(June 2017 – October 2017)

A-levels:

- Front End Web development HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery
- Back End Python, PHP, MySQL
- Multi-Platform Mobile Application Development Cordova, Ionic, Node.js, AngularJS
- Mobile Development Frameworks with Xamarin / C# using Visual Studio
- CMS Drupal, WordPress
- Mobile Native Language Java using Android Studio.
- Development of Client / Server WEB Applications in PHP and MySQL

Wyższa Szkoła Hotelarstwa i Gastronomii w Poznaniu/Poznan - Erasmus

(September 2009 – July 2010)

A-levels:

- Management A
- Tourist Market Analysis B
- Tourism Consultancy A
- Economics of Tourism and Recreation B

Instituto Superior Politécnico Gaya/Porto - Tourism Degree

(September 2006 – November 2010)

A-levels:

- Marketing
- Tourism Legislation and regulations
- Preparation of Business Plans
- Management of Human Resources

Hobbies & Interests

I'm frequently using my free time expanding my knowledge about aviation but sometimes I'm engaged in technology news, whether it can be regarding hardware, software, mobile, mobile applications or E-Sports. I'm also a frequent user of the gym and like to eat well and spend time with my friends and family.

References

Please feel free to browse through my GitHub Portfolio where you can find some of my proudest works ©

Personal and previous work references are available upon request.